<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Continuous Improvement Journal</title>
    <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Continuous Improvement Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 05:45:00 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Books I&#39;ve read in 2015</title>
      <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-06-books-from-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2016 05:45:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-06-books-from-2015/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Before starting the new year I&amp;rsquo;d like to share the books I read during 2016,
and something they thought me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love reading, I always had. I&amp;rsquo;m one of those guys that always say &amp;ldquo;the book
was better than the movie&amp;rdquo;, because that&amp;rsquo;s just how it is!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this year I developed a passion for non-fiction books, which I never
really had before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/year_in_books/2015/13240343&#34;&gt;the 13 books I&amp;rsquo;ve read in 2016&lt;/a&gt;
these are the one that thought me the most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-fail-at-almost-everything-and-still-win-big-http-geni-us-xw0:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/xW0&#34;&gt;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have chosen a better book to read at the end of the year and charge
me up for an upcoming new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;How to fail at almost everything and still win big&amp;rdquo; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Scott Adams&lt;/a&gt;,
the author of &lt;a href=&#34;http://dilbert.com/&#34;&gt;Dilbert&lt;/a&gt;, is a great little book full of
life lessons and tips, all delivered with a fun, entertaining, and a little
sarcastic style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed this book and the content resonated with me deeply. I might
soon write a focused review of what I learnt from it, but here&amp;rsquo;s the key
takeaways. Goals are for losers, systems are for winners. A system is a
continuous improvement strategy, any choice, any action you take is not toward
a goal, but towards always getting better, always gaining experience and
valuable skills. The most important system to put in place is the one to
improve your happiness. To achieve happiness, and unlocking success, you should
start by optimizing everything based one your energy, beginning with nutrition
and exercise. Finally, there is not way to remove luck from the success
equation, deal with it, but by working based using continuous improvement
systems rather than goals you can reduce luck&amp;rsquo;s contribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;How to Fail at Almost Everything and Still Win Big&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/xW0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-good-they-can-t-ignore-you-http-geni-us-1lul:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/1lul&#34;&gt;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I discovered this book thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kytrinyx&#34;&gt;Katrina Owen&lt;/a&gt;
and her talks about passion in the software industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point the book tries to make is that &amp;ldquo;following your passion&amp;rdquo; might not be
the smartest choice when choosing a career. &lt;strong&gt;Deliberate practice&lt;/strong&gt; of your
skills and &lt;strong&gt;strategy in choosing what to learn&lt;/strong&gt; will make you succeed
instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt the book was a little biased, and the example showed were too extreme,
but still the message resonated with me a lot. After reading it I started
evaluating the choice of articles to read and things to research more
carefully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully in 2016 I will be able to schedule a bit more time for deliberate
practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/1lul&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;harry-potter-and-the-methods-of-rationality-http-hpmor-com:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://hpmor.com/&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from being a brilliant fan fiction Harry Potter story, which I enjoyed
more that the original being a grown up now, this book is also sprinkled with
lessons on the rationality, the scientific method, critical thinking, and much
more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some parts have been eye openers and fired up an interest in rationality that I
knew I had but never really realised could be cultivated in such a way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://hpmor.com/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-martian-http-geni-us-3fxt:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/3fxT&#34;&gt;The Martian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This novel hooked me up with all the scientific and engineering monologues the
protagonist goes through while applying his problem solving abilities to
survive alone on Mars against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are wondering, yes, I read it before the movie was out, and yes, the
book is better than the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;The Martian&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/3fxT&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;maybe-haskell-https-gumroad-com-l-maybe-haskell:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/maybe-haskell&#34;&gt;Maybe Haskell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a book I read in light of the &lt;em&gt;deliberate practice&lt;/em&gt; strategy taught me
by &amp;ldquo;So good they can&amp;rsquo;t ignore you&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The books explores the &lt;code&gt;Maybe&lt;/code&gt; type in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.haskell.org/&#34;&gt;Haskell&lt;/a&gt;
programming language, which is a purely functional language that inspired
&lt;a href=&#34;https://swift.org/&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/a&gt; one of my daily tools of trade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding this book required a bit of effort and definitely pushed me out
of my comfort zone, but it was very rewarding and laid the foundation for a
wider set of skills and understanding of functional programming that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t
been able to get before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;Maybe Haskell&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/maybe-haskell&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-fabric-of-the-cosmos-http-geni-us-f6l:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/f6L&#34;&gt;The Fabric of the Cosmos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book entertained me and showed me how reality is so much more complex than
I&amp;rsquo;d ever thought possible, and that &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;truth is stranger than sci-fi&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s not much more I can say about this book, most of the stuff I haven&amp;rsquo;t
fully understood, and I would make a very bad and confusing job of explaining,
but it gave me hours and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find &amp;ldquo;The Fabric of the Cosmos&amp;rdquo; &lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/f6L&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://s3.amazonaws.com/cij/2015-books.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Visualization of the books I&#39;ve read during 2015&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;other-books:1672e0c8992053504c2763604193de6f&#34;&gt;Other Books&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/2dA4&#34;&gt;The Cuckoo&amp;rsquo;s Calling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/FvD&#34;&gt;Mind Hacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/3NIB&#34;&gt;The Nature of Software Development&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/17su&#34;&gt;Caves of Steel&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/3Zqo&#34;&gt;The Naked Sun&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://geni.us/9Cf&#34;&gt;The 5AM Club&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning Routine - January 2016</title>
      <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-05-morning-routine-januray-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 07:40:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-05-morning-routine-januray-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will quickly describe the current version of my morning routine, and how it
evolves, so that I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to look back at it retrospectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, you might like it and pick something from it, or you might think
something is silly, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mokagio&#34;&gt;tell me about it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I have control on my morning this is what I do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake up at 5:00am&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Smile&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink a big glass of water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the door and get some fresh air in&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do some relaxed stretching and circumvolutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read a couple of pages of the current book I&amp;rsquo;m reading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Journal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work till more or less 6:20am, focusing on what I think is the most productive thing I can bo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 to 3 rounds of &lt;a href=&#34;http://yoga.about.com/od/yogasequences/ss/sunsalutesteps.htm#step1&#34;&gt;sun salutations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make breakfast, oatmeal with nuts and blueberries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eat breakfast while reading an interesting article from my &lt;a href=&#34;https://getpocket.com/&#34;&gt;Pocket&lt;/a&gt; list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time it is almost time to leave for work. I am on client side in an
area of Melbourne full of office workers that I can reach only by tram, so in
order to avoid the peak hour &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;sardine box&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; experience I get in at around 8am
and leave at around 4pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my commute I either write, like I&amp;rsquo;m doing right now, read, listen to
podcasts, or manage my &lt;a href=&#34;https://trello.com/&#34;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt; board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it, in a month or two I expect to have a less strict time requirement to
leave for work in the morning, so I might tweak the schedule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to se in the world. Gandhi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>January 2016 Tiny Challenge: Money Tracking</title>
      <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-04-tiny-challenges-january-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jan 2016 06:03:00 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2016-01-04-tiny-challenges-january-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I learnt about &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tinychallenges.com/&#34;&gt;Tiny Challenges&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; on a recent
episode of &lt;a href=&#34;http://iohyespodcast.com/&#34;&gt;iOHYes Podcast&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept is simple, achieve big goals by breaking them down into smaller
ones, so small it would be impossible to fail. For example achieve the goal of
exercising more by challenging yourself to do 1 push-up a day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My tiny challenge for January is to &lt;strong&gt;spend 1 minute a day reviewing my
expenses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is something I have been meaning to do for a while but always failed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there is a lot of value in being aware of were your money goes in
detail. It allows you to have a better understanding of your saving capability,
and therefore plan accordingly, and also can help discover patterns or find out
where to optimise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried different apps in the past, but for this round I will use a simple
Google Spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shall report next month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to see in the world. -Gandhi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2015-12-22-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 07:19:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2015-12-22-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my birthday and this blog is my present to myself. I have other things
to do right now, but I decided to take some time to write this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past every blog I started with a declaration of intents post like this
one has always failed, but I think this time it will be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have decided to write in this web journal to share my &lt;em&gt;continuous improvement journey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am trying to say is that I want to share all the little lessons learned,
experiment, and retrospective of a journey with no destination but only one
goal, always improving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I what I might write about is diet, habits, yoga sequences, exercises,
opinions on books I read, quotes from podcasts I listen. As time goes on I think
the content might change, as my journey moves onto different areas of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure I will get a lot of value from this writing practice, both in the
form of future reference and thoughts consolidation and retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to see in the world. -Gandhi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>