<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on A Continuous Improvement Journal</title>
    <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on A Continuous Improvement Journal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 07:19:04 +1100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2015-12-22-hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2015 07:19:04 +1100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://mokagio.github.io/continuous-improvement-journal/post/2015-12-22-hello-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is my birthday and this blog is my present to myself. I have other things
to do right now, but I decided to take some time to write this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past every blog I started with a declaration of intents post like this
one has always failed, but I think this time it will be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have decided to write in this web journal to share my &lt;em&gt;continuous improvement journey&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am trying to say is that I want to share all the little lessons learned,
experiment, and retrospective of a journey with no destination but only one
goal, always improving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now I what I might write about is diet, habits, yoga sequences, exercises,
opinions on books I read, quotes from podcasts I listen. As time goes on I think
the content might change, as my journey moves onto different areas of focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sure I will get a lot of value from this writing practice, both in the
form of future reference and thoughts consolidation and retrospective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Be the change you want to see in the world. -Gandhi&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>